## Nicholas E. Torres

704 Sweetbriar dr.. • Oldsmar, FL 34677 480-650-2208 • nick.torres213@gmail.com

## **Professional Summary**

Web Developer with previous Administrative experience. Worked with several Ecommerce platforms and Consumer Management Systems. Excellent reputation for resolving problems, improving customer satisfaction, and driving overall operational improvements. Goal orientated mindset and an excellent team player. Experienced in managing data for clients and distributing information across organizations. Expertise in information technology, technical understanding, documentation, reporting, customer service and process improvement.

#### **Skills**

- HTML5, CSS, SCSS
- Node.js, Gatsby, NextJS, Express, React/React Native
- SQl, MySQL, Apache, Linux
- C++, Python, PHP
- MS office suite, Quickbooks
- BigCommerce, Shopify, Drupal, Wordpress CMS systems

#### **Education**

Hillsborough Community College Tampa, FL

Associate of Arts in Computer Science 65 credits
obtained

Land O Lakes High School

August 2009 - May 2014 Land O Lakes, FL Graduated 2014

### **Work Experience**

# Front-End Developer, July 2020 - Current Dixie Belle Paint Company - Port Richey, Florida

- Work with Senior Developer to manage website using CMS software BigCommerce and Javascript
- Pull reports on customer data and manage customer relations
- Work with marketing software to produce content
- Previous Operations Associate for three years

#### Part Machine Operator, 05/2019 to 12/2019

Nike - Beaverton, OR

- Inspected final products for defects and flaws using proper QA procedures.
- Used hand trucks, forklifts and scissor lifts to complete tasks and transport items.
- Implemented updated operating procedures for CNC machine and adjusted use to increase productivity
- and longevity.
- Supervised airbag production processes and machinery to prevent overloads and avoid malfunctions.

## Accolades

**Next Generation Venture Fund Scholar**; Selected into the Duke Talant Identification Program <sup>as part</sup> of their summer camp scholarship program

#### **Traits**

Outgoing, funny and exciting personality

Hardworking and patient

I have a Passion for motorcycles as well as playing the guitar